Daniel Ahn

Fort Lee, NJ (917) 733 - 5236 93danielahn@gmail.com Portfolio LinkedIn Github

Full stack software engineer with 7 years of experience in sales, management, customer service, and operations. With a background in the hospitality industry, I bring the necessary soft skills to work in a collaborative environment, especially in pair programming. I enjoy creating dynamic web applications by writing clean, readable code. Experienced in Ruby and JavaScript frameworks.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, Ruby, HTML, CSS, SQL Frameworks/Libraries: React, Redux, Ruby on Rails Database Management: PostgreSQL, SQLite Other: Git, GitHub, WebSockets, Semantic UI

Technical Projects

Wednesday - GitHub (Frontend) | GitHub (Backend) | Live Site

<u>Collaboration and chatting application based on Slack</u>

- Built with Ruby on Rails to control database management and React/Redux to control frontend and user experience
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and LocalStorage for user authorization and authentication
- Implemented Websockets via ActionCable to enable real time chat between users
- Applied Semantic React UI and custom CSS for styling

GrumpyBird - GitHub | Live Site

Flappy Bird inspired clone created with HTML, Javascript, and Canvas

- Created game structure and gameplay with Vanilla JavaScript and Object Oriented Programming
- Utilized Webpack to load JavaScript and bundle scripts
- Rendered components (bird, background, pipes) using HTML5 Canvas
- Created collision detection algorithm between bird and pipe to account for scores and end of game

Professional Experience

Lenwich, New York, NY

09/2016 - 06/2019

Senior Catering Sales Coordinator

- Managed and coordinated daily catering operations and sales for 18 locations and 30+ general managers
- Responsible for the largest sale in company history of (\$100K+)
- Developed and maintained client relations and yearly sales of \$3M

Lenwich, New York, NY

01/2012 - 09/2016

General Manager Candidate

- Shift Supervisor for top location with weekly sales of \$70K+
- Promoted to General Manager Candidate and then to Corporate Offices
- Trained and managed a staff of 20+ per shift

Weiss-Rohlig, Cranford, NJ

10/2015 - 01/2016

Operations Intern

- Assisted the key accounts department with sales totaling to 1/3 of the branch.
- Managed air & sea customs clearance process
- Tracked and monitored key accounts shipments

Education

Flatiron School, New York, NY

08/2019 - 11/2019

Software Engineering Immersive

Rutgers Business School, New Brunswick, NJ

09/2012 - 11/2016

Bachelor of Science in Supply Chain Management